

Ashwini Kumar Attri

IT Analyst @ Tata Consultancy Services | Android Jetpack, Kotlin Coroutines, Dagger | React Native Application Developer

GET IN CONTACT

Mobile: +91-8860555533

Email: ashwinikumarattri@gmail.com

PERSONAL DETAILS

• Total Experience 4 Years 0 Month

Current Location New DelhiDate of Birth Jan 26, 1997

Gender Male

Marital Status Single / Unmarried

SKILLS

- · Core Java
- Sqlite
- Android Application Development
- Unix Shell Scripting
- Kotlin
- Android Studio
- Retrofit
- Android
- Room
- Jetpack
- React Native Apps

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- · Android Studio
- SQLite
- UNIX Shell Scripting
- Core Java
- Kotlin
- React Native
- Visual Studio Code
- React Native Apps
- .

LANGUAGES KNOWN

- Hindi
- English

PROFILE SUMMARY

As a IT Analyst at Tata Consultancy Services (TCS), I have over three years of experience in designing, developing, and deploying consumer and enterprise applications for Android platforms. I have a strong understanding and implementation knowledge of Android native libraries and services, as well as React Native app development. I am proficient in using Android Jetpack, Kotlin Coroutines, and Dagger software tools, and have created a chat application app using Android Jetpack Compose and Firebase, which is available for download from the link. I am currently adding new features to this app, and I am always eager to learn new technologies and frameworks to enhance my skills and deliver quality products. I hold a Bachelor of Technology degree in Electrical and Electronics Engineering from Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University (GGSIPU), and have received multiple awards and certificates from TCS for my service and commitment, continuous feedback, and teaching abilities.

EDUCATION HISTORY

Graduation

Course B.Tech/B.E.(Electrical)

College Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha

University (GGSIU)
Year of Passing 2018
Grade 69.62%

Class XII

Board CBSE

Medium English

Year of Passing 2014

Grade 65-69.9%

Class X

Board CBSE
Medium English
Year of Passing 2012
Grade 70-74.9%

COURSES & CERTIFICATIONS

- The Complete SQL Bootcamp: Go From Zero To Hero
- Build A WhatsApp Chat App Clone For Android Jetpack Compose
- · Feedback Enabler Certificate
- Linux Administration Bootcamp: Go From Beginner To Advanced
- Applause Award
- CLP Faculty Award
- · Continuous Feedback Star Certificate
- Good Performance In DARPAN Training Assessment
- Service And Commitment Award
- · Xcelerate Warrior
- Master The Fundamentals And Advanced Features Of Kotlin Development

SOCIAL LINKS

· linkedin.com/in/ashwinikumarattri

WORK EXPERIENCE

Feb 2024 to Present

IT Analyst Team Lead at Tata Consultancy Services (TCS)

- Designed, developed, and deployed consumer and enterprise applications for Android platforms during three years of experience as a system engineer at Tata Consultancy Services (TCS).
- Demonstrated expertise in implementing Android native libraries and services, as well as React Native app development.
- Consistently awarded top A band every year for exceptional performance.

Jan 2022 to Jan 2024

System Engineer at Tata Consultancy Services (TCS)

I worked here on Android apps using Androdi Jetpack Compose Kotlin with new ideas and annovations. Knowledge of application development and oop's concept. Experienced in SQL,JSON Get Proficient with common Android Framework APIs. Experienced in data storage like Room Database, SQLITE Experienced in Android UI design. Experience in Android components like ACTIVITIES, SERVICES, BROADCAST RECIEVERS, GOOGLE MAPS. We follow MVVM architecture in project. I made chat application App using Android Jetpack Compose and Firebase, you can download the app from the link provided in the resume.

Jan 2021 to Jan 2022

Assistant System Engineer at Tata Consultancy Services (TCS)

My job is to develop and maintain the android application required for my project.

Jan 2020 to Jan 2021

Assistant System Engineer Trainee at Tata Consulta ncy Services (TCS)

My job is to develop and maintain the android application required for my project.

PROJECTS

Android Jetpack Compose Chat Application, 147 Day s

I am working on this appliction using Latest Jetpack Compose functionality. You can download this appliaction using below URL. I am still working on it once it is done then will upload it to the play store. https://drive.google.com/file/d/1fryGL9ISKq0PyPBu4tZ363ZdX22dRR_U/view?usp=drive_link

Blo App for iOS React Native, 90 Days

App is designed to capture the information of polling stations, PS facilities, Checklist & New Form App Features. BLO??s have the facility to add or update data for available facilities and identification of polling stations. The App is available only for 11 states (Assam, Bihar, Goa,

Uttarakhand, Gujarat, Himachal Pradesh, Madhya Pradesh, Mizoram, Rajasthan, Chhattisgarh & Telangana) as of now.

Blo App Android, 214 Days

App is designed to capture the information of polling stations, PS facilities, Checklist & New Form App Features. BLO??s have the facility to add or update data for available facilities and identification of polling stations. The App is available only for 11 states (Assam, Bihar, Goa, Uttarakhand, Gujarat, Himachal Pradesh, Madhya Pradesh, Mizoram, Rajasthan, Chhattisgarh & Telangana) as of now.

Votter Helpline App Android, 635 Days

Taking forward its continuous efforts of building an active democratic citizenry in the country, Election Commission of India has undertaken a new initiative by designing a Mobile Application for developing a culture of avid electoral engagement and making informed and ethical ballot decisions among citizens of the country. The app aims to provide a single point of service and information delivery to voters across the country. The app provides following facilities to Indian voters: